大家好, 在接下来的几个视频中, 我将给大家一个关于COOL语言的概述
Hello, in this and the next few videos I'm going to be giving a overview of COOL the
这是一个将要求你编写编译器的语言
programming language in which you'll be writing a compiler. Cool is the Classroom
COOL是教室面向对象语言的缩写, 他的一个独特设计就是
Object Oriented Language and the acronym of course, is COOL. And the unique design
COOL语言的编译器可以在相对较短的时间里编写完成
requirement for COOL is that the compiler has to be able to be written in a
我们只有一个季度, 或可能是一个学期
relatively short period of time. We only have one quarter, or in some cases, a
来让学生编写COOL语言编译器. 因此COOL语言必须
semester for students to write the compilers. And so COOL has to be
可以被很快的实现, 所以他只主要被用于进行一个编译器的教
implementable quickly. And actually since it's used primarily for teaching
世界上的COOL语言编译器的数量已经远超过COOL语言程序的数量
compilers, the number of COOL compilers in the world vastly exceeds, the number of
许多的COOL语言编译器被编写
COOL programs. So, there many, many more compilers have been written, thousands of
可能是成千上万
compilers, maybe tens of thousands of compilers have been written for COOL, but
但是只有几十个COOL语言程序被编写(译: Hello World专用语言?)
probably only some dozens, or hundreds COOL programs. And so, it's probably the
所以这可能是唯一的存在的编译器超过程序的语言
only language, in existence for which this is true, That, that, the number of
但是它确实告诉了你
compilers actually exceeds the number of programs, but it does Tell you about the
主要的设计要求. COOL语言的重点
main design requirement. It's much more important in COOL that the compiler be
是一个容易被编写的编译器. 所以这里有一些
easy to write then that it be easy to write programs in. And so there are some
语言上的怪癖, 这些都是为了让实现变得更简单而做的
quirks in the language, Things that have been done specifically to make it easier
这个语言的教学价值,
to implement where that wouldn't take away from the, the teaching value of the, of
将会使作为作为一名工作程序员的日常工作语言上
the language. But that would make it inconvenient to use the language on a
使用变得不方便, 那么, 语言中有什么呢？
day-to-day basis as a working programmer. So, what is in the language? Well it's,
我们试着设计它继承、自动内存管理提取静态类型重用
we've tried to design it so that it will give you a taste of modern notions of
这样它就能让你体验到现代的概念
extraction static typing reuse through inheritance, automatic memory management.
实际上, 当我们讲到这里的时候我们还会讲到更多的内容
And there's actually a few more things that we'll talk about when we come to
但是很多东西都被忽略了, 我们不能把所有的东西都放进去
them. But many things are left out. We're not gonna be able to put everything in the
语言和它的可实现性很快, 我们将能够覆盖一些
language and have it be implementable quickly. We'll be able to cover some
在教学中, 但不幸的是, 甚至会有一些有趣的语言想法
things in lectures, but unfortunately, there'll even be some interesting language
我们在这门课上不能讲的内容, 课程项目是
ideas that we won't be able to get to in this class. So the course project is to
构建一个完整的编译器, 特别是你要编译COOL到
build a complete compiler. And specifically you're going to compile COOL
MIPS指令集语言, 它是一种真正的指令集, 它被在20世纪80年代
into MIPS assembly language. So MIPS is a real instruction set, It was for a machine
为机器设计的, 有一个用于在任何一种硬件运行
that was designed in the 1980's. And there is a simulator for MIPS that runs on just
MIPS的模拟器, 这就使得整个项目
about any kind of hardware. And so this makes the, the whole project very
可移植, 我们可以运行你的编译器, 或者你可以生成MIPS汇编语言
portable, We can run your compiler, or you can generate MIPS assembly language and
然后MIPS汇编语言可以在任何类型的情况下进行模拟
then that MIPS assembly language can be simulated on just about whatever kind of
你可以访问的机器。这个项目被分成了五个阶段。
machine you have access to. The project is broken up into five assignments. First
你要写一个COOL语言的程序, 这个程序本身就是一个解释器
you're gonna write a COOL program. And that program itself will be an interpreter
来给你一点经验, 写一个简单的翻译。
to give you a little bit of experience with writing a simple interpreter. And
因此编译器本身就包含了我们讨论过的四个阶段
then the compiler itself will consist of the four the phases that we discussed
词法分析、解析、语义分析和代码生成。
lexical analysis, parsing, semantic analysis and code generation. And all of
这些阶段, 我要强调的是, *听不清*, 意思是我们
these phases, I should emphasize are [inaudible] compatible. Meaning that we
有单独的实现, 每个都有单独的参考实现
have separate implementations, separate reference implementations of each of
例如, 当你在做语义分析时, 你会
these. And so for example, when you are working on semantic analysis, you will be
能够获得词法分析、解析和代码生成组件
able to take the lexical analysis, parsing, and code generation components
从引用编译器中插入你的语义分析到那个框架
from the reference compiler and plug your semantic analysis into that. Framework
然后对参考组件进行测试,.
and, and test it against the reference components. And so this way if you have
这样即便你的单个组件有问题或者运行的不是很好
trouble with one component or aren't sure that your components is working very well
你在进行其他组件的编辑时也没有问题, 因为你进行的是
you won't have a problem in working on a different component because you'll be able
独立测试. 最后没有必要的优化作业
to test that independently. And finally there's no required optimization
但是我们确实有一些关于优化的建议你可以尝试实现
assignment, But we do have some suggestions for optimizations that you can
很多人都写过关于COOL语言的优化, 所以这是一个
do. And many people have written optimizations for COOL. And so this is an
如果你有兴趣学习一些关于程序的东西, 可选的程序优化
optional assignment if you're interested in learning something about program
让我们写出最简单的COOL语言程序
optimization. So, let's write the simplest possible COOL program. And the first thing
第一件事要知道的就是COOL语言的源文件, 在.CL是COOL语言的扩展, 你可以
to know is that COOL source files, and in the extension dot CL for COOL, and you can
使用任何你喜欢的编辑器来编写你的程序。我碰巧使用了Emacs,
use whatever editor you like to write your programs. I happen to use Emacs, you can
如果你喜欢的话, 可以使用其他的编辑器。每一个COOL语言的程序都必须有一个类(译: 入口类)
use some other editor if you like. And every COOL program has to have a class
叫做main, 我们先将这件事放到一边.
called main. And let's talk about that business in a second. So a class
class 关键字在COOL语言里是类声明的起始, 接在 class 关键字之后的就是类
declaration in COOL begins with the key word, class, Followed by the name of the
所以, 在本例中, main, 后面是一对花括号, 在里面
class, So in this case, main, Followed by a pair of curly braces And inside the
花括号里是所有属于这个类的东西, 以及每一个类
curly braces is where all the stuff that belongs to the class goes, And every class
声明必须由分号终止, 因此程序由一个
declaration must be terminated by a semi-colon. So a program consists of a
类声明的列表。每一个类声明都被分号终止。
list of class declarations. Each class declaration terminated by a semi-colon. So
这就是类的结构, 现在我们需要做一些事
that's the structure of a class. And now we need this class to actually do
来让我们的类里有一个方法(译: 接受self的类的成员函数就是方法), 并且让我们调用这个方法 main
something so we're going to have a method in this class, and let's call the method
事实上,  main 类的 main 方法必须始终存在, 这是
main. In fact the main method of the main class must always exist. This is the
运行启动程序的方法, 而且这个方法必须不接受参数
method that's run to start the program and furthermore this method must take no
所以主方法的参数列表总是空的
arguments. So the empty argument list for the main method is always empty. And let's
main方法它的主体总是在一对花括号中, 所以main
say the main method its body always goes in a pair of curly braces. So the main
方法总是在花括号内, 而一个类包含这样一个列表
method always goes inside curly braces. And a class consists of a list of such
声明, 这些声明必须全部由
declarations. And again, those declarations must all be separated by
分号来表示, 在这个例子中, 我们
semicolons. So in, or terminated, excuse me, by semicolons. So in this case, we
在这个类中只有一个方法, 但是仍然要有它的分号, 现在
only have one method in the class. But still has to have its semi-colon and now
我们想要这里运行点什么, 这里就是方法和代码运行的地方
we can say what we want the method actually do so this is the place for the
让我们写一个最简单的可行方法
code for the method goes and let's just have the simplest possible method the one
也就是一个值, COOL的一个表达式
that just event evaluates to the number one. Okay, so [inaudible] an expression
也就是说, 只包含一个值的代码是可以运行的
language, which means that wherever a piece of code can go, you can put an
你可以把任意表达式放在那里, 表达式可以没有显式的返回方法声明地运行
arbitrary expression, any expression can go there there's no explicit return
它只是一个函数体里的值
statement for a method. It's just a value of the method body is the value of the
在这种情况下, 我们把数字1放在这里, 这就是
methods. So in this case we just put the number one in there, and that will be the
当我们运行它时, 这个方法的值, 我们保存一下, 现在我们可以试一下
value of this method when we run it. So let's save that. And now we can try
编译这个简单的程序, 我们如何编译编译器被称为coolc
compiling this simple program, so how do we compile the compiler is called a COOL c
对于COOL语言的编译器你只需要给COOL语言的编译器一个COOL语言的源码
for the COOL compiler and you just give the COOL compiler a list of COOL source
文件, 在这个例子中只有一个文件1.cl, 回车, 哦, 我们得到了一个
files. So in this case there's just one file 1.CL hit enter and ooh we got a
语法错误所以我们必须回过头来修正这个在第3行开放花括号的错误
syntax error so we have to come back and fix that and the error said at or near the
这是一个错误, 我知道错误是什么,
open curly brace on line three there's a mistake. And I know what the mistake is,
因为我是一个至少在在COOL语言上很有能力的程序员
because I'm a competent COOL programmer, at least somewhat competent COOL
COOL语言的方法必须声明它们的返回类型, 所以我们需要在这里写点什么
programmer. Cool methods must declare their return type. So we need to put a
声明类型的语法是在方法的名称和参数列表后面加一个冒号
type here. And the syntax for the declaration is to put a colon after the
然后是类型的名称。
name of the method and the argument list, and then the name of a type. And since
我们为这个程序, 不对, 方法返回的是一个数字
we're returning the number one for this program for sorry, for this method we
也就是说main方法返回的是一个整数, 保存一下
might as well say that the main method is going to return an integer, So save that,
回到我们的编译窗口, 让我们再次编译这个程序.
Go back to our compilation window and let's compile the program again. And this
它成功编译了, 现在如果我们看一下我们的目录, 就会看到
time it compiles successfully. And now if we look in our directory we see that there
是一个叫做1.s的新文件这是程序1的汇编代码, 现在
is a new file called 1.s. That's the assembly code for the program one. And now
我们可以试着运行这段代码, 而汇编模拟器被称为spim,
we could try to run this code. And the, The, the Mitch simulator is called spin,
它只需要一个, 汇编文件, 来模拟, 所以我们只给它一个
and it just takes a, assembly file to, to simulate, And so we just give it one
1.s, 回车, 运行, 一大堆东西就打印出来了。
[inaudible] hit enter and it will run. A whole bunch of stuff is printed out. But
正如你所看到的, 它说的是COOL程序成功执行的部分原因
as you can see, it says part way down that the COOL program successfully executed, so
这很好, 然后还有一些统计数据, 比如
that's good, and then afterwards there are some statistics and things like number of
执行的指令, 大量的加载和存储, 一些分支, 这些
instructions executed, a number of loads and stores, a number of branches, those
如果我们担心性能问题, 他们就会很有用
things would be interesting if we're worried about performance if we were to
比如说, 对编译后的代码进行优化, 但是我们没有这样做
say working on the optimization of the compiled code, but we're not doing that
现在, 我们只是运行程序, 我们可以看看这个程序是否有效。
right now. We're just running programs. And we can see if this program works. So
程序运行, 成功终止了, 但实际上并没有产生任何输出
the program ran. It terminated successfully. But it didn't actually
这是因为我们没有要求它产生任何输出, 如果我们
produce any output. And that's because we didn't ask it to produce any output, If we
想要有输出, 我们必须回去修改程序, 所以
want to have output. We have to go back and modify the program again. So, so what
这个程序现在做的是, 它只是返回它的值, 但是
this program does currently, is that it just returns its value but that, but
这个值没有任何作用, 它没有打印出来, 或者类似的东西
nothing is done with that value. It's not printed out or anything like that. If you
如果你想要在一个COOL语言的程序中打印出一些东西, 你必须这样做
wanted to have something printed out in a COOL program, you have to do that
显然, 这里有一个特殊的类, 一个叫做IO的原始类
explicitly. So there's a special class built in, a primitive class called IO. And
我们可以为这个类声明一个属性(译: 允许方法调用的成员变量), 它将是一个IO类型的属性
we can declare, what's called a attribute of this class, it will be a IO attribute
它会被命名为i, 好的, 我将会是我们用来做IO的对象, 所以现在
and it will be called I, okay and I will be a object that we use to do IO. So now
在我们的main方法中, 我们可以给外字符串添加一个名为out-string的调用, #TODO我点外串
in our, main method, Here we could add a call to out-string, I dot out-string is
我们如何调用一个方法, 好的, 外串是IO类的一种方法所以我们用I来表示
how we invoke a method. Okay so out-string is a method of the IO class so we use I to
调用那个方法然后我们可以把它传递给我们想要打印出来的字符串
invoke that method and then we can pass it a string that we want printed out on the
例如, 我们可以说hello world, 好了, 现在, 我们必须决定
screen. So for example we could say hello world. Okay, And now, we have to decide
怎么做呢, 用我们的数字1, 让我再给你们看一个
what to do, with our, with our number one there. And let me show you one more
COOL语言的特性, 让我们把它放在这里, 让它成为a的一部分
feature of COOL. Let's leave the one there, and let's make it part of a
语句块, 所以语句块由一系列表达式组成
statement block. So a statement block consists of a sequence of expressions
用分号隔开, 你可以有任意数量的表达式,
separated by semicolons. And you can have any number of expressions, and the
语句块或表达式块的语义是求值
semantics of a statement block or an expression block is to just evaluate the
表达式的顺序, 以及块的值是最后一个表达式的值。
expressions in order. And the value of the block is the value of the last expression.
但是现在, 一个语句或一个表达式块必须包含在它自己的一组
But now, a statement or an expression block has to be included in its own set of
花括号, 好了, 现在这是一个COOL语言的程序我来读一下
curly braces. Okay, so that now is a valid COOL program so let me just read this for
你所以程序的主体是一个表达式块, 第一个, 执行。
you so the body of the program is a block of expressions. The first one, executes. A
对对象I的字符串调用, 它将为我们打印hello world。
out string call to the object I, which is going to print hello world for us. And
然后第二项等于1, 也就是整个的值
then the second one evaluates to one, which is the value of the entire of the
整个方法, 好的, 实际上我应该说它是block的值, 好的,
entire method. Okay, actually I should say it's the value of the block, okay, and
然后因为block是这个方法的主体块的值变成了
then because the block is the body of the method the value of the block becomes the
整个方法的值, 因此将从这个方法调用返回。
value of the entire method, So one will be returned from this method call. So let's
保存一下, 回到这里, 让我们再编译一次, 看起来像我
save this. Go back over here and let's compile this again. So, Looks like I
没能保存它, 让我们编译这个, 我们看到我们有一个语法错误, 所以它
failed to save it. Let's compile this and we see we have a syntax error. And so it
在第4行, 我们有一个语法错误, 在我们的右花括号附近。
says on line four, we have a syntax error at or near our closing curly brace. And
这里的问题是, 一个语句块, 或者表达式块由一个
the problem here is that a statement block, or expression block consists of a
序列或一系列由分号终止的表达式, 我们忘记了
series or a sequence of expressions terminated by semi-colons, and we forgot
要用分号来终止序列中的最后一个表达式, 所以我们必须
to terminate the last expression in the sequence by its semi-colon, So we have to
加上这个, 现在我们应该能够编译这个, 然后看它
add that. And now we should be able to compile this, and lo and behold it
编译正确, 然后我们可以运行它, 现在我们看到, 哦, 我们得到了另一个
compiles correctly, and then we can run it. And now we see, oh we got another
错误, 我们有一个, 当程序运行时它抱怨我们有一个
mistake. So we have an, when the program ran it complained that we have a
被调度的void, 所以在第4行, 我们的分派对象是一个没有的对象
dispatched void. So that on line four, our dispatch was to an object that didn't
存在, 你可以看到这里的调度调用, 它不存在,
exist. And, you can see the dispatch call right here to I, and it doesn't exist,
因为, 事实上, 我们忘记为I分配一个对象了, 所以这里我们声明I为
because, in fact, we forgot to allocate an object for I. So here we declare I to be
输入IO, 但它实际上并没有创建任何对象, 这只是说
of type IO, but that doesn't actually create any objects. That just says that it
创建一个变量名, 但实际上我没有一个值, 如果你想让我
creates a variable name I but I doesn't actually have a value. So if you want I to
实际上有一个值, 我们要把它初始化到某个东西上, 这样我们就可以
actually have a value, we have to initialize it to something. So we can
将其初始化到一个新的IO对象, 而这里的新对象是您分配新对象的方式
initialize it to a new IO object. And new here, is the way you allocate new objects
在COOL语言和新中总是使用类型参数所以在这个例子中创建了一个
in COOL and new always take a type argument so in this case were creating a
IO中的新对象, 并将其分配给这个对象i, 注意这里
new object in type IO and were assigning it To this object i. And notice here that
我是a, is a, 在Java中被称为字段名, 这就是我们所说的
I is a, is a, is what would be called a field name in Java. It's what we call an
属性是COOL语言的, 所以, 这些是数据el, 数据元素,
attribute in COOL. So, so these are the data el, the data elements of the, of the
类, 所以类可以有两个事物的名称, 属性, 或者
class. And so the class can have both of names of things that are so, attributes or
包含值的字段以及可以执行计算的方法。
fields that hold values as well as methods that can perform computation. [sound]
保存一下, 然后切换回来, 现在我们再编译一次, 它仍然是
Let's save this and switch back. And now we'll compile this again. So and it still
编译, 现在我们可以运行它了, 现在它运行, 低看, 你可以
compiles. And now we can run it. And now it runs, and low and behold, as you can
看下面的第三行, 顶部, 它打印出hello world, 然后
see down there third line from the, the top, it prints out hello world. And that
看起来有点丑, 因为成功的执行消息是在
looks a little bit ugly because the, the successful execution message is on the
和我们的hello world消息一样, 我们来解决这个问题, 我们回到这里。
same line as our hello world message. So let's fix that. Let's come back over here.
在我们的字符串中, 我们可以添加一条新线, 在字符串的末尾, 所以
And in our string here we can add a new line. Okay at the end of the string, so
反斜杠N是如何在字符串中写入新的行字符。
backslash N is how you write a new line character in the string. Save that, come
回到这里, 让我们编译, 如果你不知道Unix bang会重复这个
back over here let's compile. So if you don't know Unix bang will repeat the
前面的表达式, 前面的命令以与您相同的前缀开始
previous expression the previous command that began with the same prefix that you
在爆炸之后键入, 所以我要运行最后一个命令, 从C开始, 也就是
type after the bang. So I want to run the last command that began with C which is to
编译, 然后我想运行从S开始的最后一个命令
compile and then I want to run the last command that began with S which is to run
自旋, 现在我们可以看到, 所有的hello world都是单独在一行上的。
spin. And now we can see there it is all nice hello world is on a line by itself.
让我们继续, 让我们把所有这些声音都清除掉, 让我来展示一下
Let's continue now, let's [sound] clear all this out [sound]. So let me just show
你在同一个程序上有一些变化, 我要做的是重写
you a few variations on the same program. What I'm going to do here is just rewrite
它有两种不同的方式, 我只是举例说明了
it in a couple of different ways. So I just illustrate a couple of features of
COOL语言, 让你更熟悉语法, 也可以展示一些
COOL and get you more familiar with the syntax, and also just show some
做同样的事情的另一种方法, 你知道, 这个, 这个,
alternative ways to do the same thing. So you know this, this. A block here of, of
表达式是一种笨拙的方式来实现Hello World程序, 所以
expressions is kind of a clumsy way to, to implement the Hello World program. So
我们把它去掉, 我们把这个去掉, 把这个去掉
let's get rid of that. Let's get rid of the, the block. Let's get rid of the one
在这里, 好了, 让我们把表述体再一次变成一个表达式,
here at the end. Okay, let's just make the statement body a single expression again,
现在我们要解决的问题是这些类型是不匹配的, 但是
and, and now the problem we're going to have is that the types won't match. But
为了说明这一点, 让我给你们展示一下让我们用一个点CL,
just to illustrate that, let me show it to you so let's do COOL C of one dot CL, and
你会看到, 在这里, 抱怨的是, 推断出的返回类型
you'll see here that in complains that the inferred return type of the IO of the
方法main不符合声明的返回类型INT, 所以返回
method main does not conform to the declared return type INT. So coming back
在这里, 对于程序, 编译器算出了这个表达式,
over here, the, to the program, The, the compiler figured out that this expression,
我点出了字符串, 产生了一个输入IO的对象, 所以它返回I对象
I dot out string, yields an object of type IO. So it returns the i object as the
结果对这个表达式求值, 这与它的类型不匹配。
results evaluating this expression. And that does not match the type it. And so
当然, 编译器会说, 嘿, 这些类型有问题,
naturally, the compiler says, hey, something's wrong with the types. Well,
这很容易修复, 我们可以改变返回类型或者主要方法
that's easily repaired. We can just change the return type or the main method to say
它返回的是IO的类型, 我们回到这里, 看看现在是否
it returns something of type IO. So let's go back over here and see if that now
所以, 我们编译程序, 然后我们在输出上运行旋转, 是的,
works. So, we compile the program. And then we run spin on the output, and yes,
所有的东西都像预期的那样工作, 现在, 我们不需要对
everything still works as expected. Now, We don't have to be so specific about the
在这里输入, 因为我们实际上并没有使用方法主体的结果
type over here, since we're not actually using the result of the method body for
任何东西, 我的意思是, 程序在打印字符串时就会退出, 我们可以
anything. I mean, the program just exits once it prints the string. We could have
允许我们在这里有更多的灵活性, 我们可以直接声明结果类型
allowed ourselves more flexibility here. We could've just declared the result type
对象是类型对象的main。所以Object是类层次结构的根。
of main to be of type Object. So Object is the root of the class hierarchy in COOL.
每一个类都是对象的子类, 让我们回到h, 保存一下
Every other class is a subclass of Object. So let's come back over h, let's save this
首先, 然后我们可以回到编译窗口, 我们可以编译它。
first. And then we can come back over to our compilation window. We can compile it.
我们可以运行它, 它仍然有效, 所以现在我们可以做的另一件事是
And we can run it and it still works. So now another thing we can do if we want, is
我们可以观察到, 在这里, 我们声明的这个属性, 这个字段我不是真的
we could observe. Here that this attribute that we declare, this field I isn't really
必要的, 在这里, 我们分配, 你知道我们有一个特殊的名字, 当main
necessary. Here we, we allocate, you know we have a special name I when the main
对象被构造来运行这个程序, 一个新的, 听不清的对象被分配给我
object is constructed to run the program, a new [inaudible] object is allocated to I
然后在主方法中使用, 我们可以做所有的
and then that gets used in the main method. We can actually just do all of
在主方法内部通过分配一个新的, 听不清的对象
that inside the main method itself by just allocating a new [inaudible] object right
这里, 然后在那个对象上调用字符串, 好了, 这也可以。
here and then calling out string on that object. Alright, So this should also work.
让我们来检查一下, 它会编译, 然后看, 它会腐烂, 好的, 那么
And let's check it out. So it compiles. And lo and behold, it rots. Alright, So
回到这里我们再来解释一遍, 或者更多的东西
coming back over here let's illustrate one more, or a couple more things that we
可以这样做, 我们也可以说, 听不清从IO继承, 所以我们有
could do. So, we could also say that [inaudible] inherits From IO. So we have
为了调用out字符串方法, 在某处有IO功能, 所以我们
to have the IO functionality somewhere in order to call the out string method. So we
我们通过创建一个单独的IO对象来实现这一点, 但是现在我们可以
have been doing that by creating a separate object of type IO. But now we can
说, 好吧, 主要的物体本身就是它本身, 它具有所有的
say well just the main object is itself. And something that has all the
IO的能力, 从IO继承而来, 如果你见过, 听不清
capabilities of IO by inheriting from IO. And if you've seen any [inaudible]
在此之前的语言是一个熟悉的概念, 这里的主要内容是
language before this will be a familiar concept. So main here gets all the
除了它的属性和方法之外, IO的属性和方法
attributes and methods of IO, in addition to whatever attributes and methods of its
拥有它将拥有的, 而不是, 必须要分配一个新的IO对象
own that it will have. And now Instead of, of having to allocate a new IO object in
调用字符串的顺序, 我们可以在self上调用它, 它的名字是
order to call out string, we can just invoke it on self, Which is the name of
当主方法在其他语言中运行时, 当前对象被调用
the current object when the main method runs In other languages self is called
这个, 好的, 我们保存它, 让我们重新编译这个, 它
this. Okay, and so let's we saved it, so let's go over and compile this. So it
编译, 编译, 然后运行, 对吧？最后一个例子, 我们没有
compiles, it compiles and, and it runs, right? So last example here, we don't have
在这个调度中命名self。有一个特性允许我们调用a
to name self actually in this dispatch. There's a feature that allows us to call a
方法没有显式地命名它所发送的对象
method without explicitly naming the object on which it's dispatched and
默认为self, 所以如果在分派中没有指定对象那么它就是一个分派
defaults to self, so if no object is named in a dispatch then it's just a dispatched
所以这也应该起作用, 声音, 确实是这样的, 这就结束了
self. So this should also work. [sound], And indeed it does. So that concludes our
第一个例子, 在接下来的几个视频中我们会看到一些更复杂的
first example. In the next couple of videos we'll look at some more complex
COOL语言编程的例子。
examples of COOL programming.